# **AVINASH TAMBY**

Current Position: Economic Researcher at Aix-Marseille School of Economics  $\square$  USA: +1 (908) 255-3376  $\diamond \square$  atamby1@gmail.com  $\diamond \square$  France: +33 (0)6 69 20 24 57

### **BIOGRAPHY**

I have 6 years of experience as a credit risk modeler. I spent 5 years developing PD, LGD, and EAD models to inform the NPV of future cash flows on a portfolio which insures \$1.3 trillion of debt. I now work as a researcher analyzing financial fragmentation and inequalities in the euro area.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Aix-Marseille School of Economics**

Marseille, France 2022 - Present

Economic Researcher

- .1
- · Assess how banking fragmentation creates unequal financing opportunities in the euro area
- · Examine the role of bond and equity markets in the distribution of income and wealth
- · Evaluate the role the ECB can play in reducing inequalities through financial integration

# Summit Consulting, LLC

Washington, DC, USA

Credit Risk Modeler

2017 - 2021

- · Forecast the NPV of future cash flows for FHA's \$1.3 trillion mortgage insurance fund
- · Developed PD and LGD models to evaluate the Economic Net Worth and Capital Ratio of the fund
- · Communicated model updates to the Model Risk Governance Board and FHA Commissioner
- · Coordinated the monthly ETL procedure to ingest, process and clean 100GB of mortgage data
- · Performed stress tests to assess the fund's ability to face adverse economic developments
- · Designed sensitivity scenarios to test model robustness to various interest rate and HPI environments
- · Worked directly with OMB to provide loss mitigation options to borrowers affected by COVID-19
- · Implemented model updates to improve model estimations of insurance claim losses

## **EDUCATION**

## Aix-Marseille School of Economics

Marseille, France

Master of Arts Degree in Economics - Empirical and Theoretical Economics Track 2021 - 2023

The Johns Hopkins University

Baltimore, MD, USA

Bachelor of Science Degree in Applied Mathematics and Statistics

2012 - 2016

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

· CIVIS AMSE-UAM Master's Exchange Week (Link to Certification)

2021

· SAS Certified Specialist: Base Programming Using SAS 9.4 (Link to Certification)

2020

· General Assembly Data Science Immersive (Link to Certification)

2017

### PRESENTATIONS & PUBLICATIONS

· Thompson, S., Book, T., & Tamby, A. (2018). Natural Language Processing: A Powerful Tool to Analyze Open-Ended Survey Responses. Presented at the 73rd Annual American Association for Public Opinion Research Conference, Denver CO. (Link to Abstract)

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

 ${\bf Advanced\ Proficiency} \qquad \qquad {\rm Python},\,{\rm R},\,{\rm SAS},\,{\rm SQL}$ 

Intermediate Proficiency LATEX, Stata, AWS (EC2, Glue, Redshift, S3)

## LANGUAGES

Native Fluency English, French

Limited Working Proficiency Spanish

Last updated: August 2022